JOHN JANG

Product Designer

iscolbe9675@gmail.com

https://www.iohniang.ca/

SUMMARY

A Product Designer, graduated fresh from York University in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, actively developing a career in crafting user experience while carrying a year of experience in web development. Coming with a background in Neuroscience, Education, and Software Development, I have been participating in the process of building digital products either from the scratch or by redesigning what already exists, while considering the development perspective such as the User Interface development. Despite short periods of involvement in the past projects, I have been successful in delivering the results that meet the expectations of stakeholders. My strengths include strategic designing, initiating projects, and leading communications with internal and external teams. By nature, I am analytical, perceptive, and enjoy problem-solving. Outside of work, I am a runner, dancer, and a potential traveler.

EXPERIENCE

Product Designer Internship The Sakhi

06 / 2024 ~ Present | Remote, Toronto

- Designed culturally specific shopping experience in the pilot phase
- Conducted regular design critique sessions with Shopify developers to refine features and functionality based on feedback
- Identified 8+ user flow pain points and improved the shopping experience through data-driven adjustments aligned with business goals

UX/UI Design Apprentice TeleVU Innovation

06 / 2022 ~ 08 / 2022 | Remote, Toronto

 Conducted user research with 30 participants gathering insights that informed feature prioritization and usability

VOLUNTEER

Product Designer OperateEase

09 / 2024 ~ Present | Remote, Toronto

 Developed a comprehensive design system to standardize UI components and hosted UX Design workshops to align with stakeholders and gather insights from users



08 / 2023 ~ 09 / 2024 | Remote, Toronto

08 / 2023 ~ 09 / 2024 | Remote, Ioronto

UX/UI Design Apprentice Tech Fleet Professional Association

04 / 2023 ~ 07 / 2023 | Remote, Toronto

EDUCATION

UX Design

York University North York, Ontario

Web Development Bootcamp

Pream Coding Academy

Remote, Toronto

Psychology & Neuroscience University of New Brunswick

Fredericton, NB

TOOLS & SKILLS

Figma, Figjam, Miro, Wireframing, Sketching, Typography, Prototyping, Mock-ups, A/B Testing, Usability Testing Waterfall, User-Interface Design, User Research HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.js, React, Vite, MongoDB, Express.js, Axios

OTHER LINKS

My Web Development Portfolio
My Github Profile